２人は　今　１分１秒を惜しんで 修行しているからな。
Th-Thank you very much...
また会おうと伝えてくれ。
Why did you not call for help?
おう！
Here...
ではな。 それじゃあね。
And here... You're covered in blood!
クラピカを　よろしく頼む。
What is this creature?
あいつは冷静に見えて　無鉄砲。
What do I want
頭がいいのに 考えなしのとこがある。 見たところ　あんたには 心を開いてるみたいだし
to do with her?
おぉ！
the northeast elevator down to the
basement, to search for Palm.
ありがとうございました！
If you find her, escape without us. Right.
クッ　あの野郎 本気で全部　買う気だ
If the King and his three Royal Guards
are in the throne room, we proceed with the plan.
こっちの予算も 完全に読まれているし…
The problem is, what if they're not there?
残り１個…　クソっ！ 必ず落としてやる！
You're really hung up on that... What are the chances of that happening?
「また会えるし 今は修行　頑張れ」ってよ。
Well, it's highly unlikely. But the unusual happens pretty often.
え　よかったのに　そんなの…。
Aren't you contradicting yourself?
クラピカが ヨークシンを出るなら安心だって 喜んでたじゃねえかよ。
We researched the enemy's behavior extensively
before deciding on a day for the attack.
そりゃそうだけど 黙って行っちゃうなんて…。 ほれっ！ ゼパイルからだ。
When you're waiting for someone to be
in a certain place, at a certain time, that's typically when the unexpected happens.
あいつも 「また会おう」って言ってたぜ。
In my old job, I saw this all the time.
えっ!?　ゼパイルさんも？ ああ　約束通り きっちり１億に戻してくれてな。
The unusual always happens
on the day you've chosen.
ホントだ。 これで質に入れた ハンターライセンスを取り戻せるな。
In my old job, I could wait for the next chance, to ensure my success.
うん　やっぱり　すごい人だね ゼパイルさんって。
But this time, that isn't an option. We can't wait.
ハンターライセンスってやつは
So we should take time now to decide
質屋が即金で １億出すってことは
how we'll act in different situations.
もっと　しかるべきとこで売ったら 桁２つは違うんじゃねえか？
Even if they aren't in the throne room,
if they're still in the palace, it's okay.
あぁ！ そうだ！ 俺もプロハンターになって ライセンス売りゃあ　いいんだよ！
Pitou's En is enough to cover the palace and
its surrounding courtyards, and then some.
そうすりゃあ　おめぇ 借金どころか　一気に利子生活！ よっしゃ！　そうと決まれば 善は急げだ！
So if we sense that creepy aura when we enter, we'll know that they're there.
ハンター試験の準備　準備！ １６番　６０２億で 『グリードアイランド』落札！
From there, we just follow that
sinister aura to where it feels densest, and they'll be at its center.
ありがとうございました。
The question is what we do if
we don't sense Pitou's aura.
６０２億だとよ
In other words, what we do
if they aren't in the palace.
すげぇな　結局　７本とも 全部　落札しちまった。
Or if they're in the palace,
but they aren't using En.
その代わり　個人資産の 半分を失ったそうだぜ
Would they be in the palace, but not using En to guard the King?
[TV]　先日　３０５億で落札した 『グリードアイランド』を 何者かに強奪された バッテラ氏でしたが
That's what happened when
Knov-san infiltrated the palace! Huh?
めげることなく　昨日は２７８億
Yes, that's what I can't make sense of.
今日は　なんと６０２億ジェニーで 落札いたしました。
According to Colt, Knov saw Pouf's aura.
フンっ！ [TV]　そこまでするのには 何か理由があるんでしょうかね？
The Royal Guard never leaves the King's side.
[TV]　ゲームクリア後に　隠し財宝が 示された地図が出るとか
So if Pouf was there, the other two were
also in the palace with the King.
巨大な龍が現れて 願いごとを １つ叶えてくれるとか まことしやかな噂が 飛び交ってますがね。
Then, why did Pitou stop
using the puppets and En, leaving Pouf to handle security, which allowed Knov to infiltrate the palace?
まいどあり
I believe the reason has to do with
how Pitou's power works...
帰ろ…。
Then we should ask Colt.
結局　全ての『グリードアイランド』を 競り落とした　バッテラ氏！
I'd guess that during that time,
Pitou was healing someone.
彼は同時に　プレーヤーを 募集しておりますが
Healing?
期日は今日！ 会場前は　すでに 長蛇の列になっております。
I told you that Pitou was the
one who restored Kite, yes?
お待たせいたしました。
Thinking back, I don't believe Pitou
used En during that period.
これより　プレーヤー選考会を 始めたいと思います。
Thus, healing must require a
great deal of concentration.
すでに　ご承知の通り このゲームに参加するには 念能力が不可欠！ そこで審査の方法ですが
So while healing someone, Pitou cannot use En or the puppets.
まず　おのおのの 「念」を見せていただき
Now it makes sense.
我々が　独断で合否を決定する …という方法を とらせていただきます。
Which means that someone, most likely the King or one of the
Royal Guard, was injured and
審査を担当いたしますのは プロハンター　ツェズゲラ氏です。
required healing, so the En
and puppets disappeared. But hold on...
マネーハンター　ツェズゲラ！ 奴が動いてるってことは…
Who would have been able to
injure one of those monsters?
このゲーム 見返りもデカいってことだぜ
True... An internal dispute?
では　早速　審査に入る。
Maybe the King injured one of the Royal Guard? No, that's impossible.
１人ずつ　ステージの上で 「練」を見せてもらう。
There is no chance that Pitou
would endanger the King
ステージは シャッターとカーテンで仕切り
by removing that En to heal someone else!
他の者には　様子が 分からないように配慮する。
I guarantee it.
３２名　合格者が出た時点で
Which means that the one injured... ...was the King!
審査は終了とする。
I see... What you're saying makes sense.
では　審査を受ける方は こちらから　どうぞ。
But then the bigger question
is who injured the King.
説明は　あれだけかよ…
Yep, so our conclusion was...
それでは　１番目の方　どうぞ。
The King injured himself?!
最低限の説明 分からないことだらけ でも　周りの奴らは 当然のように行動している
Under what circumstances
would that have happened? We don't know why, but it's the only explanation.
あいつらは分かってるんだ こちらの問いに対し 決して返答などないことを
I'll admit that I didn't question our
sudden stroke of luck too much...
俺達がすべきこと…
But that chance was only possible
under abnormal circumstances.
それは　説明されたことから 残りを推察し　最善を尽くすこと
Are they starting to lose control?
きっと　この行動の選択も含めて 過程は全て審査の一部 会場には　約２００人の志願者
That isn't good... I'm starting to think something's
going on inside the palace.
１００人近くが列をつくり 審査待ち
We will now begin moving to the palace.
その周りを ５０人以上が取り囲み 機をうかがっている そして　２０人ほどは動かない
Citizens of sector A-1, assemble in
Diego Plaza at once.
どのグループの判断が 正しい？ 次の方　どうぞ。
The citizens of the other sectors
should prepare to move out.
おかしい…
Oh, they're starting to file out.
すでに　１０人近くが 中に入ったのに
They've begun their march...
誰一人　出て来ない 入った奴ら 全員　合格したってことか？
Ten hours until midnight, when the selection starts.
マズいぞ… 俺達も並ぶべきか？ てんで話にならない。 ん？ え？
In twenty-five hours, tomorrow afternoon at three, five million humans will fill the palace grounds.
今　並んでる連中と その周りを取り囲んでる連中さ。
Has the situation in Peijing changed? I thought it was only one skilled enemy,
but now there are a bunch.
特に行列の周りで ウロウロしてる奴ら…。
So there are reinforcements.
まさか　不合格者が 戻って来るのを期待して 中の様子を聞く気かねぇ？
They may try to use the celebration
as cover to approach us.
ちゃんと下調べが済んでいて 普通に頭を働かせれば
Then the danger will be greatest
during the selection.
順番を競って 並ぶ意味など　ないことに 気づきそうなもんだが。
Yes, since the King will be
participating in the selection.
((つまり　新たなプレーヤーを 投入できないのだよ))
Our greatest concern is
((だから 新たなプレーヤーは厳選する))
the King somehow being taken beyond our reach.
そうか！　この選考会では ３２名も合格者は出ない。 その通り。 １０年以上も　クリアした者が いないとされるゲーム。
Assuming that they have a Nen
user capable of translocation, and that that person can use the ability
to isolate the King somewhere else...
しかも　前のプレーヤーが 生きてる限り 後の者は参加できない仕組み。
That means at least one of us must stay
ならば　保険の意味でも
by the King's side during the selection.
より有望な挑戦者が 現れた時に備えて
The King won't allow it.
いくつか空席を残しておこうって 考えるのが普通。
As it is, he's been upset by how
close we've stayed to him.
今回の審査で選ばれるのは
Then we guard him secretly,
without his knowledge.
恐らく２０人ちょっと ってとこだろう。
We need someone to stay just close
enough to monitor his surroundings
今　並んでる連中と　その周りで たむろしてる奴らは 俺が見ても明らかにダメ！
while still carrying out his own role in the selection...
見込みがあるのは　開始と同時に 迷わず席を立った数人と からくりを理解して席に残り 集中してる俺達。
Whose size won't attract attention, who won't get absorbed in an amusing task...
なぁ？　そっちの坊ず。 あ…。
Very well, I am the best choice for this.
ゴン…　お前　気づいてたのか？
Strictly by process of elimination, of course...
いや　何となくだけど…。
What's wrong?
主催者側から考えたら せっかく集めた人達の実力は
Their presences have completely disappeared.
全員　確かめておきたいって 思うのが人情かなって。
I can't sense any residual aura.
アハハ…　そりゃそうだ 坊ず　おめぇの勝ち！ いや　大したもんだよ 自分のことわりを持って
They must be using Zetsu to hide
among the marching humans.
それに身を委ねるってのは なかなか　できねえんだ。 正解への道が　険しく危ないほど
Hey.
バカと利口の両方を 兼ね備えてねえと
There are so many people...
前へ進めなくなる。
Around a hundred per building.
次の方　どうぞ！
They must have been packed inside.
俺の名はプーハット まっ　よろしくな。
Then if we conceal our presences, they can only assume that we're
hiding among the citizens.
ああいう うんちく　たれんのに限って 落ちたりすんだぜ。
Maybe they'll cancel the march?
プハ…。 聞こえるよ…。
No way.
でも　確かに あいつの言う通りだ
That would mean delaying or
even canceling the celebration.
俺は　最善の手にこだわって 理屈で考え過ぎた
Which would imply the King had
accepted defeat and compromised.
先に行くぜ。 うん！　頑張って。
The Royal Guard won't let that happen.
冒険しなきゃ　前に進めない それだけ危険な道
The celebration will begin as scheduled,
no matter the cost. Tomorrow morning, at 3 PM!
((１００％やれると 確信した時だけ実行し
Once the humans began to move, my puppets could no longer tell them apart...
それ以外は待て))
Should I recall them?
((俺達の最も重要な仕事は 待つこと)) ((勝算もなしに 自分の能力を見せるなど
No, giving the enemy free
rein would be dangerous.
最も愚かな行為だぞ)) それは　親父の理屈… 俺は　もう殺し屋じゃ　ない
Have the puppets join the soldiers that
are guiding the citizens, as a deterrent.
あの時の「練」が　実力の 全てではないことを見せてくれ。 じゃ　行くぜ。
'Sup? As expected, the puppets have joined the march.
オーラを電気に!?
There are six entrances to the
rooms that lead to the palace.
理論上は確かに可能 …が　あり得ん！ ゼロから　この４日間で 覚えたなどということは… どう？　もう少し見るかい？
We'll avoid the entrances in front of the
palace, where security will be tighter, and wait by entrances A, B,
and C, behind the palace.
いや　よかろう…　合格だ。 うしっ！ しかし　一朝一夕で 身につくことじゃ　ない！
Once we've entered the rooms, the only exit will lead inside the palace. What? You scared?
拷問に近い強力な電気を 浴びる修行だけで
Don't be absurd. I merely want to be sure we're prepared.
数年はいるはず　お前は一体…。 強力な電気ね。
Waiting by the entrances involves
quite a lot of risk.
生まれた時から浴びてたぜ 家庭の事情でね。
But if we enter the rooms too early,
we won't be able to exit until midnight.
７人か…
And we can't use cell phones near the palace, since the Ants will pick up on the signal.
やっぱり　おっさんの読み通り 受かってるのは 真っ先に動いた奴らと 席で待ってた奴ら
I think it's dangerous to spend hours
waiting inside the rooms, not knowing if there have been
accidents or changes in the situation.
さて　ゴンは大丈夫かな？
But you're the one who said it was
risky to wait outside the palace.
ゴン！ あっ！　キルア！ よかった！　選ばれたんだね！
I'm the only one who can freely
enter and exit these rooms.
当然よ！　今の音　お前か？
If anything happens, I'll tell you.
うん！
For now, you should rest here.
まったく… 末恐ろしい子供達だ。
Will you be okay? I shouldn't have any problem
investigating the area...
さて　とりあえず おめでとうと言っておこう。 君達２１人には　『グリードアイランド』を プレーする権利を与える。
Even if I'm right beside the palace, as long
as I'm out of range of Pitou's En...
ゲームをクリアした場合の報酬は ５００億ジェニー。
But you should be careful.
詳細は　契約書に書いてあるので
Pitou doesn't use a standard circular En.
夕方５時の出発まで よく目を通し サインを済ませておくように。
It changes shape like an amoeba,
giving it extended range.
カンパイ！
That's what Kite came in contact with.
とりあえず　第１関門　突破だな！
And it was probably deliberate...
これ ちょっと見てほしいんだけど。 何だ？　契約書か。
It's a fighter's instinct to want to know
how strong the opponent is.
要約すると３つだな。 １つ　ケガをしたり 死んだりしても文句言わない。
And his instinct led him to misjudge their strength.
２つ ゲーム内から持ち帰った物は
In some areas, that En can
stretch two kilometers.
全て　バッテラ氏に所有権がある。
Make sure you stay out of range.
３つ　ゲームをクリアした者には
Don't worry about it.
５００億ジェニーの報酬を与える。
In this room, I'm the one who most fears them.
特に　問題は　ねえだろ。 うん！
I won't do anything crazy.
じゃ　サインして終わりだな。 大事なのは　２つ目だな。
I promise you that.
ゲームの中から 現実に持ち帰って来る何か。 奴が　大枚はたいて求めてるのは その何かだ。
We will now head to the palace.
「何か」って　何だ？ 何だって渡すよ。
Any person who leaves their line
will be shot on the spot.
俺が欲しいのは　物じゃ　ない。
Move out!
じゃあな。 レオリオ　試験　頑張ってね！
Pitou...
次　会う時は　お医者さんだね。
You knew that Komugi was being attacked?
おめぇ　そりゃ最短でも ４年　会わねえってことか？
Yes, I was monitoring the area with En.
俺達は　もっと早く ゲームクリアするつもりだけどな。
However, I determined that there was no threat
to Your Majesty, so I ignored it.
フンっ　負けねえよ。
From now on, monitor Komugi's surroundings, and deal with any threats at once.
さて　始める前に 少しだけ補足しておこう。
What is
このゲームは　ソフトそれぞれが 独立してるわけではない。
that?
どのハード機からスタートしても 行き着く先は　皆同じ。
Wing scales?
１つのバーチャルエリアに 世界中から 参加できるものと 考えてもらっていい。 プシュ。
The wind is carrying the scales of
his wings toward the citizens...
では　メモリーカードを配布する。
That means...
その前に順番を決めてもらいたい。 順番？
As I thought...
ゲームエリアには １人ずつしか入れないのだ。
They all look completely vacant and dazed.
中で　もめることのないよう ここで順番を決めてもらう。
Those scales have a hypnotic effect.
じゃ グパジャンで決めようぜ。
Stay in line as you advance!
よし！　１番！
Stay in line!
おや？　君は確か… セーブデータを持っていたね。
Once you reach your position, wait for orders. Do not move!
クッソ　１７番目かよ！
Simple orders delivered repeatedly,
while tanks roll in the background
使うかね？
can easily seep into a mind exhausted
from hours of marching...
安心したまえ。 どのセーブデータでも 最初に行き着く先は　皆同じだ。
It's the perfect situation for using hypnosis!
ジン… このゲームは ジンが残したメッセージ 信じて進むよ！
Once the selection begins,
and blood starts to fly, they will continue to quietly stand in place. Until it's their turn.
うむ　ならば指輪をはめて ゲームをスタートしたまえ。
Hypnosis? I see...
ゴン！　俺が行くまで スタート地点で待ってろよ。
If they're brainwashed, the citizens won't run. But this works out for us.
おぉ！
If we make a lot of noise, we won't have to worry about citizens panicking. Ah!
おぉ…。
There won't be any stampede of humans
falling over each other to escape.
「Ｎｏｗ　Ｐｌａｙｉｎｇ」の文字が出たら 次の者がスタートだ。
That's a big boon. Assuming that over half of the people
will be in place at midnight, we would have expected a stampede to
leave tens of thousands of casualties.
あ…。
Our biggest concern has been addressed. We can go crazy.
『グリードアイランド』へ　ようこそ ゴン＝フリークス様ですね。
Six hours to go.
これよりゲームの説明をします お聞きになりますか？
Everyone's here. Have you heard from Palm?
うん。 このゲームでは その指輪をはめていれば
No.
誰でも使える魔法が２つあります。
Oh...
「ブック」と「ゲイン」です。
We'll keep waiting until half
an hour before go time.
それでは指輪をはめた手を 前に出し
If we knew what's inside before
going in, it'd be very different...
「ブック」と唱えてください。
Yeah.
ブック。
They both look composed.
このゲームは　指定されたカードを 集めるゲームです。
Killua, in particular, shows none of the mental weakness he
displayed when we fought.
それは集めたカードを 収める本になります。
I'd almost say he's brimming with confidence.
最初のページを 開いてみてください。 それぞれのポケットに 番号がふってあります。
But for some reason, he seems on the verge of fading away.
そのポケットには　同じ番号の カードしか入れることができません。 これを「指定ポケット」といいます。
No, I don't have time to worry about others.
ページを どんどん　めくってください。 あっ！　番号がない！
I'm the one suffering from the most anxiety.
はい　そのポケットには どんな番号のカードも 入れることができます。
The fate of humanity rests on me...
それを 「フリーポケット」といいます。
Colt is a good guy...
指定ポケットは　ナンバー０から ナンバー９９まで １００個あります。
Meleoron and Ikalgo both have good hearts.
それに対し フリーポケットは４５個です。
It doesn't matter if they're humans or Ants.
Everyone has a heart.
指定ポケットに入る１００枚の カードをコンプリートすること。
That's what I want to believe.
それが　このゲームの クリア条件となります。
Hopefully, the King also has one.
１００枚のカードを 集めればいいんだね。
But some of them must be killed...
そうです　厳密に言うと １００個のアイテムを
If we don't kill them, we'll be killed!
カード化して　その本にそろえる ということです。 カード化？
Kite, it's almost time.
例えば　剣というアイテムを 入手した場合
I promise to turn you back...
それは手にした瞬間に カードに変わります。 逆に　カードをアイテムとして 使いたい場合は
By defeating that Ant.
「ゲイン」という魔法を使います。
He's fired up... I'll focus on providing support.
「ゲイン」…。 ただし　一度「ゲイン」で アイテムに戻したら
So no one can interfere in your battle...
二度とカード化されませんので ご注意ください。
Using my new Kanmuru technique.
再びカード化したい場合は 再度　入手する必要があります。
My body feels heavy.
ここまで　よろしいですか？
I'm suffering from days without rest...
うん…　何とか。
On a scale of 1 to 100, my current
condition would be 40...
これ以外にも２つ カード化できないケースがあります。
No, 35...
１つは　そのアイテムの カード化限度枚数が
But I can't be whining now.
マックスになっている場合です。 「カード化限度枚数」？
With Knov out, I'm the only one left.
はい　このゲーム内に存在する アイテムには 全て カード化限度枚数があります。
I was hoping to fight at full strength, but it's easier to accept my fate this way.
例えば　カード化限度枚数が ３のアイテムの場合 そのアイテムを　３人のプレーヤーが それぞれカード化してしまったら
I'll focus on playing the decoy and
drawing my target from the King.
たとえ４人目が そのアイテムを手に入れても
I'm sorry, Morel and everyone...
カードにできないということです。
But I can't bring myself to go.
そして　もう１つ！ え？ カードは 本に入れずに１分経つと
I'll take a look outside.
この場合も 二度とカード化はできません。 お分かりになりましたか？ うん…　何とか。
So two minutes is the longest
I can hold my breath...
最後に　最も重要な注意点。
Given how tense I'll be inside, my limit
will probably be, at most, half that.
う…　そろそろ覚えきれないぞ
Good enough...
もしも　プレーヤーが 死んでしまった場合
One minute is more than enough time!
本と指輪は破壊され 中のカードは全て消滅します。
Tomorrow, at midnight, I will be reborn.
死んじゃったら そんなの関係ないと思うけど
A few days ago, I couldn't have
dreamed of such a life.
以上で説明は終わりです あとはゲームを進めながら
Thank you, Killua.
より詳しい情報を ご自分で入手してください。
I promise to carry out my mission for you!
うん　分かった　ありがとう。
Tomorrow will be my birthday!
ジン!?
I am the King.
これは　俺が仲間と作ったゲームだ 楽しんで行ってくれ。
But who am I?
だが　俺の元へ　たどり着く 手掛かりがあると思ったら あいにくだったな。 俺は　ただ　このゲームを 自慢したいだけだ。
Why was I brought into this world?
理由が　どうであれ ここまで来た以上 あるアイテムを手に入れない限り ここから出られない。
Time's up... Let's go!
『グリードアイランド』に 足を踏み入れたゴン
Palm...